Surendra Singh

er.surendra87@gmail.com Mobile: +91 7024837045

https://www.linkedin.com/in/ssingh05/

Summary

Data Scientist with 6+ years of experience in solving critical business problems by discovering insights and applying solid technical knowledge in data analysis, machine learning models, deep learning and statistical algorithms on structured and unstructured data. Adept at prototyping, deploying (in production) and maintaining data science models while having a strong contextual understanding of data. Have planned, conceptualized, executed and managed projects from scratch.

Academic Qualifications and Certifications

- Master's Degree in Computing & Information System, **The University of Greenwich London** (2011- 201)
- Bachelor of Engineering in Electrical and Electronics Engineering University Institute of Technology RGPV
 Bhopal (2005 2009)

Certificate:

- Statistical Learning (Stanford University)
- Structuring Machine Learning Projects (Deeplearning.ai)
- Neural Networks and Deep Learning (Deeplearning.ai)
- Data Science in Python (University of Michigan)
- Python for Data Science and Machine Learning (Udemy)
- PRINCE2® Foundation in Project Management

RELEVANT SKILLS & TOOLS

- Area of Expertise: Machine Learning, Data Analysis, Application development.
- Programming Languages & Tools: Python, R, SQL
- Python Libraries: NumPy, SciPy, Pandas, Scikit-Learn, Matplotlib, Seabron and others.
- Application Development: Django, Flask, NGINX, Docker
- Models: Linear Regression, Logistic Regression, Random Forest, Decision Tree, KNN, SVM, K-Means Clustering, NLP, Neural Network

Employment History

Team Lead, Reliance (June 2019)

- Build NLP Modle to predict mssing category .
- Developing Application in Django and deploy by Docker
- Develop Video Stream Application.
- Video Analysis, Converting Video to text and text Analysis.
- Prepare data and information for user analysis.

Module Lead, Mindtree, Bangalore (February 2017- June 2019)

- Developed predictive models from raw data for various customers.
- Prepare data and information for making regular report data analysis.

- Worked on many statistical modelling approaches.
- Perform data analysis for complex data files.
- Perform data manipulation.
- Establish operation strategy in a team for improving sales.
- Perform quantitative analysis of product sales trends to recommend pricing decisions.

IT Consultant, ITC Infotech, Pune (March 2016 – February 2017)

- Prepare data and information for making regular report data analysis.
- Develop image classification model using OpenCV.

Developer (Contract), Premier Media, London (April 2015 to August 2015)

- Working as a Python/Django developer
- Web Scrapping
- Collecting data from various sources for marketing strategy.

Developer (Contract), Explore Group, London (May 2014 to February 2015)

• Working as a Web developer

Web Developer, Williams Lea, Norwich (UK) (September 2012 to February 2014)

Working as a Web/Application developer

Personal Details:

DOB: 05/05/1987